Luis Cano Irigoyen

Objective

Computer Science student and developer looking forward for opportunities related to Artificial Intelligence / Neural Networks, and web/app/software development, looking forward to make innovative products with positive impacts in the world.

Relevant skills and tools

Languages

Spanish: Native

English: Professional working

proficiency C1

French: Limited working proficiency B1

Skills

- Data Analytics
- Digital Marketing
- Project Management
- Artificial Intelligence
- Neural Networks, Machine Learning, Deep Learning
- Web applications
- Object Oriented Programming
- Market Research
- SEO & SEM
- Writing
- Front-end and Back-end
 Development
- Game Development
- UI/UX
- Colaborative Projects
- Operations Management

Programming Languages and Tools

Python Tensorflow
C++ scikit-learn
Unity

SQL

AWS

WordPress

Node.js / React.js

MATLAB

HTML5

Google Ads

WordPress

GitHub

Figma

CSS3 Arduino IDE

R / RStudio Excel

Creative front-end and back-end developer with work experience in web development –making and designing sites for multiple companies–, in online marketing –being proficient in Search Engine Optimization and Search Engine Marketing–, and in app development –working with React and Unity to develop UI/UX layouts, functions, features as well as game mechanics.

Currently my research topics include deep learning, forecasting and data analytics.

Throughout my studies have also worked in multiple projects with other large companies ranging from developing software, API servers, neural networks, web pages, databases, games, statistics for data science, and project planning (SRS).

Education

BSc in Computer Science — currently enrolled

Tecnológico de Monterrey (Monterrey Institute of Technology)
Monterrey, Nuevo León, México Expected Graduation year: 2023

International Baccalaureate Diploma

Liceo de Monterrey Centro Educativo Monterrey, Nuevo León, México

Experience

Graduation year: 2019

Digital Analyst

Forte Industria // May 2021 – Present

- I currently work as a Digital Analyst, Web Developer and SEO Analyst at Forte Industria —an online retailer of industrial machinery.
- Successfully introduced the new company into the digital market, starting from nothing and reaching 1.5k monthly users on the website in a year.

Unity Developer Internship

<u>Gamejam</u> // Jun 2021 – Aug 2021

- Implemented UI/UX layouts from Figma into Unity for a now published Game.
- Developed an idea/brief into a game prototype, creating: Player mechanics, Enemies AI, Obstacles and interactions with them, Editor Tool for Level Building.
- Worked with a large team providing ideas for others and implementing received feedback into my own projects.

Web Developer & Marketing Analyst

Pixelwork Agencia Web // Jul 2019 - Apr 2021

- Utilized WordPress for building company websites.
- Worked with Ahrefs and Yoast to increase with success the organic traffic value of multiple domains, as well as making their websites healthier (less errors and increased quality).
- Created and Managed multiple Google Ads campaigns.

Contact information

Email:

<u>lcanoi0510@gmail.com</u>

Phone: 81 2349 2066

Find me at:
Website LinkedIn
GitHub

Projects

You can find further information, images, and code when allowed, of most of these projects in my website https://lcanoi.netlify.app/

■ Natural Language Processing for Time Predictions — CEMEX

Website

- o I developed a Multilayer Perceptron to predict effort of a given task of CEMEX (how much time would it take employees to solve said task). Implemented a Natural Language Processing and Neural Network solution to read text of a task and make a prediction of time.
- Researched deep learning structures to determine the most adequate solution.
- Achieved a great prediction accuracy stated by CEMEX, 67.63%, working with dirty and very limited amount of data for training and testing.
- Project components developed: React.js client, Nest.js server, FastAPI server, SQL database,
 Python Tensorflow Keras neural network, Tokenizer.

■ Gamification Based E-Learning — Ternium

Website

- Developed a digital platform that allows Ternium employees to train in various areas of the industry through gamification, cutting training costs and increasing employee engagement.
- Project components developed: React.js website with user/admin authentication, MySQL database, python API, Unity Game (Trivia / Endless runner).

■ Genome Sequence Analyzing — Data Science

Github

- Made a research to identify genetic differences in genome sequences between young and old patients, to find out why younger people are getting colon cancer.
- 。 Using Big Data, R Studio and Computational Biology tools. Worked with NCBI and PubMed data.
- Discovered a gene, JAK1, which has T cell mutations only on young patients, which could be a cause of increasing colon cancer.

Cryptocurrency forecasting with News Scraping and Deep Learning — Big Data

- Currently working on a project for cryptocurrency time series prediction, using news scraping, a
 neural network for sentiment analysis, and a neural network for predictions with historic value,
 sentiment and context variables of the currency.
- Multi-attention based LSTM for sentiment analysis, decoder autoencoder LSTM for prediction.
- In development, working and researching with a team of undergrad students with feedback of experts in the area.

Contact information

Email:

<u>lcanoi0510@gmail.com</u>

Phone: 81 2349 2066

Find me at:
Website LinkedIn
GitHub